Adrian Martin Senior Full Stack Engineer

• Hialeah, Florida 33015

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/adrian-m-41a8b6259/

s live:.cid.e5633f6d5650b892

PROFILE

Self-motivated Software engineer with 10 years of experience working on multiple projects. Passionate and hardworking with a penchant for meeting deadlines. Experience includes collaborating in team-driven environments to create high-performance web applications that customers and businesses love.

SKILLS

Back-end Technologies and Frameworks

NodeJS, ExpressJS, Ruby on Rails, Microservices, Elastic Search, Kafka, Spring Boot, Laravel, PHP, Java, Python, RESTful API, GraphQL, OAuth, Webpack, C#, ASP.net, Drupal, Go

Content Management System

Directus, WordPress, Shopify, Strapi, Sanity

Version Control Tools

Git(Github, Gitlab), CVS, SVN, VSS(Visual Source Safe)

Front-end Languages and frameworks

ReactJS, Angular, AngularJS, VueJS, React Native, NextJS, NuxtJS, EmberJS

Database Management Systems

MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, Microsoft SQL, Oracle, Redis

DevOps

AWS, Azure, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Ansible

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Jul 2020 - Mar 2023 Raleigh, North Carolina, **United States**

Senior Software Engineer, Albet *⊘*

- Built and maintained large-scale applications using ReactJS, Angular, Vue, Node/ExpressJS, Laravel, Drupal, MySQL, and Microsoft SQL from scratch resulting in a 20% increase in application productivity and a 15% increase in conversion rates.
- Led a team of 5 developers in delivering several high-visibility projects, including a mobile-first redesign of the website and a real-time product customization tool.
- Learn and adopt cutting-edge new technologies into our project: Implement Typescript on server environment by re-writing the whole backend project. Implementing testing case and automation testing workflows using Jest, Mocha, Jasmine, Cypress, etc.
- Extensive interaction with the clients on requirement gathering and estimation on Sprint planning and user stories tracked in Agile methodology with Jira, Trello, etc.

Jul 2017 - Jun 2020 Charlotte, North Carolina, **United States**

Senior Software Engineer, Axim ⊘

- Developed and maintained e-commerce & healthcare platform using React, Angular, NodeJS, MySQL, and MongoDB.
- Collaborated with a team of 10 developers to deliver the project on time and within budget, while ensuring high quality and maintainability.
- Implemented advanced features such as real-time streaming, client-side form validation, robust error handling, and logging to improve the stability and reliability of the application.
- Worked in Agile methodologies for incremental development to deliver better applications and used Jira and Git as version control and tracking units.
- Environment: ReactJS, Redux, React Hooks, React Native, Redux-Saga, Thunk, Angular, Vue, JWT, Typescript, Javascript, HTML5/CSS3, Ajax, Bootstrap, Github, Gitlab, Jasmine, MongoDB, SQL, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Agile.

Jul 2013 - Jun 2017 Ankeny, Lowa, **United States**

Software Developer, Pratum *⊘*

- Designed, Developed an internal management system using HTML, CSS, JSON, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, and Ajax, PHP from scratch.
- · Worked closely with our business product owners on an agile team to fully understand requirements, provide feedback, and request clarification as needed.
- Executed the SEO project single handily in Agile. Involved in requirement and analysis with the clients plus developing, enhancing & testing the application using Javascript, CMS tool, TFS, HTML5, and CSS3.
- Integrated MongoDB for lifetime backend database storage across multiple clients and developed sorting algorithms for adding and updating thousands of requests at a time.

• Participated in team meetings with the remote team and corporate clients to understand the needs of a new implementation. Participated in daily team meetings and scrum meetings.

EDUCATION

2008 – 2012 San Francisco, United States Bachelor's degree - Computer Science, San Francisco State University

GPA: 3.7/4.0

CERTIFICATES

- AWS Certified DevOps Engineer Professional
- Free Code Camp Full Stack Development Certification
- Dynamics CRM Application Certification
- Professional in Web Accessibility (PWA)
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer (MCSD)
- Microsoft MTA Database Certificate Fundamentals
- Certified Web Developer (CWD)
- Certified Front End Developer (CFED)